<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Christopher Vierheller</title><link>https://packet-warrior.net/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Christopher Vierheller</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://packet-warrior.net/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://packet-warrior.net/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://packet-warrior.net/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey, I am Christopher (26 years old) from Frankfurt (Germany) and I am an IT professional who is currently employed as a Cybersecurity-Consultant working in the german banking industry as SOC-Analyst to analyze SIEM-Alerts and help improving the SIEM-Infrastructur for the client.
Previously, I worked as an IT systemadministrator, IT support and IT project worker.&lt;br>
This allowed me to gain technical experience with a wide range of IT systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I found strong interest in networks and cybersecurity in my role as systemadministrator and currently I am studying for certificates to soon be able to work in the field of networking &amp;amp; network security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently pursuing the compTia Security+ certification with an anticipated passing date of end of July.
Afterwards I want to finish the CCNA Certification (Cisco) in a time frame of 4 months which I started to learn for in the last months in my role as systemadministrator.&lt;br>
I am passionate about IT in general and looking forward to connect with people and have conversations about our great field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My published articles will have a focus on networking and cybersecurity but occasionally there could always be a general IT topic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to keep in touch using your preferred social media – I have linked to all my social media accounts to the left!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Update (21.07.2022): I just passed my compTia Security+ certification&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have a good read !&lt;br>
Christopher&lt;br>
&lt;img src="https://packet-warrior.net/about/Portrait.png"
width="480"
height="720"
srcset="https://packet-warrior.net/about/Portrait_hu5b2b2577cbb710ad11347d81281a75b6_334854_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://packet-warrior.net/about/Portrait_hu5b2b2577cbb710ad11347d81281a75b6_334854_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Portrait1"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="66"
data-flex-basis="160px"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://packet-warrior.net/archives/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://packet-warrior.net/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://packet-warrior.net/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://packet-warrior.net/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>